Mss.B.H142.1-3
American Philosophical Society
David Hall papers, 1745-1822
Mss.B.H142.1-3
American Philosophical Society
0.25 Linear feet Ca. 100 items.
Ca. 100 items.
This collection includes four letter books (1750-1767), containing principally business correspondence with Benjamin Franklin (42 letters), William Strahan (193 letters), and the stationers Bloss & Johnson, London, Johnson & Unwin, London, and Hamilton & Balfour, Edinburgh. There are also accounts current, 1748-1768 (2 vols.), of which one contains Edinburgh. There are also accounts current, 1748-1768 (2 vols.), of which one contains Franklin and Hall's account for printing done for the province of Pennsylvania, 1756-1767, with an index volume to these accounts; records of bills of exchange remitted to London, 1745-1752 (1 vol.); there are about 90 loose letters (some are photocopies) mainly from William Strahan to Hall, 1745-1775, concerning business matters, as well as English and American politics. Included in this group is correspondence relating to Hall and his publishing partnership, and his son William's partnership with Sellers. One additional volume is a photocopy of Franklin and Hall's "Work Book No. 2," 1759-1766, 1782-1789, from the original at the New York Public Library (B H142.lf).
Hall, David, 1714-1772
Box 1
Scope and Contents Note
The David Hall Papers are comprised of correspondence and records related to the creator’s printing business, especially his partnership with Benjamin Franklin. This collection includes four letter books (1750-1767), containing principally business correspondence with Benjamin Franklin (42 letters), William Strahan (193 letters), and the London stationers Bloss & Johnson, and Johnson & Unwin, as well as Hamilton & Balfour, stationers in Edinburgh.
Typical of this correspondence is Hall’s November 20, 1764 letter to the Scottish printer, stationer and bookseller Alexander Kincaid of Edinburgh, complaining that the Bibles he had received in a recent shipment had a single clasp, and that he expected future shipments of testaments to come “double Clasped”.
In a December 16, 1765 letter to his long time friend the publisher William Strahan in London, Hall mixes business and politics. Much of the letter comprises an extensive order of books for the Library Company of Philadelphia, but Hall ends the correspondence with a dire warning about the Stamp Act. He urges that it be repealed, since he says the people of the Colonies will risk their lives and fortunes to oppose it.
There are also about 90 loose letters in the collection (some are photocopies) mainly from Strahan to Hall, 1745-1775. In one of these letters dated March 13, 1756, Strahan comments on Hall’s description of “the miserable Situation with Respect to the Indians” during the Seven Years War. He encourages his friend that “the Assistance which you may expect from Europe this Summer will effectively protect you from both your Indian and French Enemies.” Most of these letters concern business matters and English and American politics. Included in this group is correspondence relating to Hall and his publishing partnership, and his son William's partnership with William Sellers.
There are also accounts current, 1748-1768 (2 vols.), of which one contains Franklin and Hall's account for printing done for the province of Pennsylvania, 1756-1767; another is a book of accounts current with various (mostly London-based) stationers, book-sellers and printers with an index volume to these accounts; and records of bills of exchange remitted to London, 1745-1752 (1 vol.). Another volume is a photocopy of Franklin and Hall's "Work Book No. 2,” a record of their printing business between 1759-1766. The entries for 1782-1789 probably relate to printing work done by the firm of [William] Hall and Sellers. The original Work Book No. 2 is at the New York Public Library (B H142.lf).
Finally, there is a one volume Receipt Book (131 leaves) for the Hall & Sellers firm, pertaining to its papermaking and printing activities in the Philadelphia area from 1771-1776; pressed flowers are interleaved, named and noted.
Tables of contents available
Note—The December 10, 1757 letter from William Strahan to David Hall is missing from the box.
Early American History Note
This collection consists of a range of materials related to the business history of David Hall, printer. The collection contains four outgoing letter books of David Hall to business correspondents (Xeroxed from a private collection), account books for the shop (Xeroxed from a private collection), and incoming correspondence, primarily from William Strahan (mostly originals). Hall’s letter and account books provide a clear record of the print shop’s business. The correspondence of William Strahan, which is the only original manuscript portion of the collection at the APS, is often long and detailed. The letters from Strahan touch on matters relating to family and friends, business, and politics. Strahan’s letters occasionally discuss his business dealings in other colonies, and mention other printers such as James Rivington. Strahan almost always ends by giving Hall accounts of politics in London, which may have been used to disseminate news in the PA Gazette. These accounts also provide insight into the perceptions and beliefs of a prominent Londoner during the imperial crisis.
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
Received and accessioned, 1948 (1948 82484); 1969. See in-house shelf list for additional accession numbers and dates.
Biographical/Historical note
David Hall (1714-1772, APS 1772). Printer and business partner of Benjamin Franklin. Scottish journeyman printer invited by Benjamin Franklin in 1743 to Philadelphia to join his printing firm. Subsequently, he entered into partnership with Franklin in 1748. Hall ran Franklin’s newspaper, the Pennsylvania Gazette so successfully, that in 1766, he bought out Franklin and formed the new printing firm of Hall and Sellers.
Hall was born in Westfield, Scotland in 1714, just outside of Edinburgh. At the age of fifteen he was apprenticed for five years to the Scottish printing firm of John Mosman and William Brown. In a letter dated January 17, 1743 Hall’s friend William Strahan inquired on his behalf to an American correspondent James Read of Philadelphia about openings for printers in the colonies. He recommended Hall, who he described as “obliging, discreet, industrious and honest.” Read showed the letter to his brother-in-law Benjamin Franklin, who was looking for a journeyman printer; and on July 10, Franklin invited him to come to Philadelphia. Franklin acquired not only a competent journeyman printer, but also a reliable correspondent and agent, who could supply British publications for sale in the Philadelphia printing office. In 1748, Franklin, busy with other interests and public affairs, made Hall a partner. Afterward Hall maintained the printing business for the firm of Franklin & Hall, also editing and publishing Franklin’s newspaper the Pennsylvania Gazette. In February 1766 Franklin sold his share in the business to Hall. Later in May of that year, Hall brought William Sellers, who had been his journeyman printer, into the business to establish the partnership of Hall & Sellers. The new firm carried on government printing, including paper money for the Province of Pennsylvania. Hall also had a bookselling and stationery shop related to his printing shop.
Hall quickly acclimated to his new city of Philadelphia. On January 7, 1748 he married Mary Leacock/Laycock in Christ Church. The couple had four children. Hall was a founding member of the St. Andrews Society of which he was an active member, printing its constitution, rules, and membership roll in 1769. He was also a member of the Union Library Company, later absorbed by the Library Company of Philadelphia. He was a Mason and in 1762 was Master of his lodge No. 2 in Philadelphia. He was also a contributor to the Pennsylvania Hospital, the Silk Society and to the College of Philadelphia. Although elected to the American Philosophical Society on March 8, 1768, he showed little interest in the Society and appears never to have attended a meeting. Nevertheless, Hall was selected for a committee in 1771 to determine the selling price for the first volume of the Transactions, which was published that year. Hall died in Philadelphia on December 24, 1772, and was buried in the Christ Church cemetery.
Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790; Hall, William; Sellers, William, 1725?-1804; Strahan, William, 1715-1785; Account books.; American Revolution; Business and Skilled Trades; Business Records and Accounts; General Correspondence; Great Britain -- Politics and government -- 18th century.; International Affairs; Letter books.; Papermaking -- Pennsylvania -- Philadelphia -- 18th century.; Printers -- United States -- Philadelphia -- 18th century.; Printing and Publishing; Printing industry -- Accounting -- United States -- 18th century.; Receipt books.; United States -- Politics and government -- To 1775.
- Papers
  - Letter to David Hall, March 9, 1745; 8 1/4" x 13"; Strahan, William, 1715-1785
    Scope and Contents note
    London, A.L.S. 3p. and add. Lists material for Dr. Franklin. Business. FILM54-61 FRAME 43
  - Letter to David Hall, June 22, 1745; 8" x 13"; Strahan, William, 1715-1785
    London, A.L.S. 2p. and add. List books for Hall tied together in "Mr. Franklin's trunk." Mr. Franklin "seems...to have a very good heart, as well as to be a man of honour & good sense." FILM54-61 FRAME 44
  - Letter to David Hall, Aug. 23, 1745; 6" x 7 1/2"; Strahan, William, 1715-1785
    London, A.L.S. 1p. and add. FILM54-61 FRAME 45
  - Letter to [David Hall], May 25, 1751; Strahan, William, 1715-1785
  - Letter to [David Hall], July 27, 1751; Strahan, William, 1715-1785
  - Letter to [David Hall], Aug. 26, 1752; Strahan, William, 1715-1785
  - Letter to Davie [Hall], June 14, 22, 1753; 6 1/2" x 8 1/4"; Strahan, William, 1715-1785
    London, A.L.S. 3p. and end. Wishes to be remembered to Mr. Franklin and his family. Business. FILM54-61 FRAME46
  - Letter to Davie [Hall], Nov. 1, 1753; 7" x 9"; Strahan, William, 1715-1785
    London, A.L.S. 4p. "Copy." Family affairs. Business.
  - Letter to Davie [Hall], Nov. 12, 1753; 7 1/4" x 9"; Strahan, William, 1715-1785
    London, A.L.S. 1p. and end. "Copy." Bill of exchange sent to Mr. Franklin. Contains also letter from Strahan to Hall, Feb. 2, 1754. FILM54-61 FRAME47
  - Letter to Davie [Hall], Dec., 1753; 7 1/2" x 12 1/2"; Strahan, William, 1715-1785
    London, L. 3p. and end. "2d copy." Same text as letter of Nov. 1, 1753.)
  - Letter to David Hall, Feb. 1, 1754; 7 1/2" x 12 1/2"; Strahan, William, 1715-1785
    London, A.L.S. 2p. and add. "Copy." Business. Contains also letter dated Feb.12, 1754.
  - Letter to Davie [Hall], Feb. 2, 1754; 7 1/4" x 9"; Strahan, William, 1715-1785
    London, A.L.S. 2p. On same sheet with letter from Strahan to Hall of Nov. 12, 1753. Same content as letter of Feb. 1, 1754.
  - Letter to David Hall, Feb. 12, 1754; Strahan, William, 1715-1785
    London, A.L.S. Portion of page. On same sheet with letter from Strahan to Hall, Feb. 1, 1754. Business.
  - Letter to Davie [Hall], May 9, 1754; 7 1/2" x 10"; Strahan, William, 1715-1785
    London, A.L.S. 2p. and enc. - 1p. and end. Type for Mr. Franklin's nephew in Connecticut. Encloses invoice of books for Mr. Hall, May 7, 1754. FILM54-61 FRAME 48
  - Survey of land for Robert Johnson, May 9, 1754; Photo-reproduction (1972 683ms) From original owned by Mrs. Stimson, 1969.; George Trenchard
  - Letter to Davie [Hall], Aug. 3, 1754; 7 1/2" x 10"; Strahan, William, 1715-1785
    London, A.L.S. 1p. and end. "Copy." "Mr. Franklin's books are in one of your trunks..." Business. FILM54-61 FRAME49
  - Letter to Davie [Hall], Oct. 11, 1754; 7" x 9"; Strahan, William, 1715-1785
    London L. 2p. and end. "Copy." Sends material to Hall "directed to Mr. Franklin, postmaster." Acknowledges letter from Franklin; material shipped for B.F.'s nephew in Connecticut. Contains also letter dated Nov. 9, 1754. FILM54-61 FRAME50
  - Letter to Davie [Hall], Nov. 9, 1754; 7" x 9"; Strahan, William, 1715-1785
    London, A.L.S. Portions of 2p. On same sheet with letter from Strahan to Hall, Oct. 11, 1754. Desires to be remembered to Mr. Franklin. Business. FILM54-61 FRAME50
  - Letter to Davie [Hall], March 3, 1755; 7 1/4" x 9"; Strahan, William, 1715-1785
    London, A.L.S. 3p. and end. British fleet for defense of America against the French. Business.
  - Letter to David Hall, Aug. 20, 1755; 7" x 9"; Strahan, William, 1715-1785
    London, A.L.S. 1p. and add. ---- Copy of same letter. 1p. and end. 7 1/4" x 12 1/2" L. The war in America. Business.
  - Letter to Davie [Hall], Oct. 1, 1755; 7 1/2" x 9 1/2"; Strahan, William, 1715-1785
    London, A.L.S. 2p. ---- Copy of same letter. 2p. and add. 8 1/4" x 13" L. FILM54-61 FRAME51
  - Letter to David Hall, Oct. 25, 1755; 8 1/4" x 13"; Strahan, William, 1715-1785
    London, A.L.S. 1p. On Same sheet with copy of letter from Strahan to Hall, Oct. 1, 1755. Asks for Hall's opinion of his "proposals to Mr. Franklin about the Gent. Mag." Business. FILM54-61 FRAME51
  - Letter to David Hall, March 13, 1756; 7 1/4" x 9"; Strahan, William, 1715-1785
    London, A.L.S. 2p. and add. "Copy." Defeat of Braddock; Indian and French enemies. Thinks Quaker mode of government absurd.
  - Letter to Davie [Hall], Sept. 11, 1756; 7" x 9"; Strahan, William, 1715-1785
    London, A.L.S. 4p. Encloses letter to J.Read which he wants Mr. Franklin to see. "...Mr. Franklin...has really acquired immortal honour in the service of his country." Business. FILM54-61 FRAME52
  - Letter to [David Hall], Dec. 10, 1757; Strahan, William, 1715-1785
    A.L. 2p. B. Franklin assures him that Pennsylvania will be defended against the Indians. Regards to Mrs. Franklin and Sally. Transcribed in letter of Dec. 12, 1757. FILM54-61 FRAME53
  - Letter to David Hall, Dec.12, 1757; 7-1/4x12; Strahan, William, 1715-1785
    London, A.L.S. 2p. and add. Transcribes letter of Dec. 10, 1757. Mentions B. Franklin. FILM54-61 FRAME53
  - Letter to David Hall, Feb. 22 & June 10 1758; 8 1/4" x 13", 8" x 13"; Strahan, William, 1715-1785
    London, A.L.S. 2p. and add. ---- Copy of same letter 3p. and add L.S. FILM54-61 FRAME54
  - Letter to David Hall, June 10, 1758; 7 1/2" x 10"; Strahan, William, 1715-1785
    London, A.L.S. 3p. and end. ---- Copy of same letter. A.L.S. 1p. and add. ---- Another copy with letters of Feb. 22 and July 1, 1758. L. 2p.
  - Letter to David Hall, July 11, 1758; 7 1/2" x 10"; Strahan, William, 1715-1785
    London, A.L.S. 2p. and add. ---- Copy of same letter A.P.S. 3p. and add. Trickery of Rivington; book trade with America. Mr. Franklin and son are in the country. FILM54-61 FRAME56
  - Letter to David Hall, Sept. 26, 1758; Strahan, William, 1715-1785
    London, A.L.S. 1p. and add. "Copy." Mentions Mr. Franklin. Business. Regards to Mrs. Franklin and Sally. FILM54-61 FRAME57
  - Letter to Davie [Hall], March 24, 1759; Strahan, William, 1715-1785
    London, A.L.S. 3p. End. ---- Copy. 4p. Business and friendly letter. Mentions B. and Mrs. Franklin. FILM54-61 FRAME58
  - Letter to David Hall, July 17, 1759; 7 1/2" x 10"; Strahan, William, 1715-1785
    London, A.L.S. 3p. and add. ---- Copy of same letter. L. 3p. and end. 7 1/2" x 10" FILM54-61 FRAME59
  - Letter to David Hall, Oct. 6, 1759; 7" x 9"; Strahan, William, 1715-1785
    London, A.L.S. 1p. and add. "Copy." Mentions meeting Messrs. Franklin in Edinburgh where they were presented with the freedom of the city; probably be a month or more before they return to London. Business. FILM54-61 FRAME60
  - Letter to David Hall, Dec. 17, 1759; 7 1/2" x 9 3/4"; Strahan, William, 1715-1785
    London, A.L.S. 2p. and add. Mr. Rivington. Has company of Messrs. Franklin as often as they can spare it. Business. Printed in part: R.D.Harlan. "Wm. Strahan..." Lib. Quartarly, XXXL, 242. FILM54-61 FRAME61
  - Letter to David Hall, Jan. 7, 1760; 6 1/2" x 8 1/4"; Strahan, William, 1715-1785
    London, L. 2p. and add. "Copy." Mr. Rivington fails. Business.
  - Letter to David Hall, Philadelphia, Jan. 7, 1760; Strahan, William, 1715-1785
    London, L. 2p. and add. End. "copy" concerning the ruin of the man who has been trying to undersell Strahan. Paid W. Franklin as Hall ordered. FILM54-Family FRAME30
  - Letter to David Hall, Philadelphia, Feb. 13, 1760; Strahan, William, 1715-1785
    London, A.L.S. 1p. and add. Seal. End. Friendly business letter. Paid W. Franklin the money. FILM54-Family FRAME31
  - Letter to David Hall, Feb. 13, 1760; 7" x 9"; Strahan, William, 1715-1785
    Rivington's failure. Business.
  - Letter to David Hall, April 5, 1760; 6 1/2" x 8 1/4"; Strahan, William, 1715-1785
    London, A.L.S. 1p. and add. "Copy." Rivington plans to set up business in New York. Messrs. Franklin are in good health. Business. FILM54-61 FRAME62
  - Letter to Davie [Hall], June 21, 1760; 7 1/2" x 10"; Strahan, William, 1715-1785
    London, A.L.S. 2p. and add. and enc. - 1p. Mr. Rivington. The war. "Mr. Franklin has got great reputation here from his pamphlet in regard to North America." Business. FILM54-61 FRAME63
  - Letter to David Hall, Sept. 1, 1760; 7 1/4" x 12"; Strahan, William, 1715-1785
    London, A.L.S. 1p. and add. The war. Business.
  - Letter to Davie [Hall], Nov. 17, 1760; 7" x 12"; Strahan, William, 1715-1785
    London, A.L.S. 3p. and end. Mentions Messrs. Franklin. Contains invoice of books sent Hall, Oct. 24, 1760. Business. FILM54-61 FRAME64
  - Letter to David Hall, Feb. 26, 1761; 7" x 9"; Strahan, William, 1715-1785
    London, A.L.S. 1p. and add. Introduces the bearer, Mr. William Miller.
  - Letter to Davie [Hall], Feb. 26, 1761; Strahan, William, 1715-1785
    London, A.L.S. 3p. End. Friendly business letter. Dr. Franklin and son are well. FILM54-61 FRAME65
  - Letter to Davie [Hall], July 15, 1761; 7 1/2" x 9 1/2"; Strahan, William, 1715-1785
    London, A.L.S. 3p. and end. Is at Bromley with Dr. Franklin. English politics. Business Mentions W. Franklin. FILM54-61 FRAME66
  - Letter to David Hall, July 24, 1761; 7 1/2" x 9 1/2"; Strahan, William, 1715-1785
    London, A.L.S. 1p. and add. ---- Copy of same letter. A.L.S. 1p. and add. 7 1/2" x 9 1/2" "Copy". The war. Business. Mentions Dr. Franklin, William, Sally, and Mrs. Franklin. FILM54-61 FRAME67
  - Letter to Davie [Hall], Oct. 6, 1761; 7 1/2" x 10"; Strahan, William, 1715-1785
    London, A.L.S. 3p. and end. English politics. Mentions Dr. Franklin. Business. Mentions Mrs. D. Franklin. FILM54-61 FRAME 68
  - Letter "to the editor of the London Chronicle", Oct. 19, 1761; 7 1/2" x 10"; Strahan, William, 1715-1785
    Richmond, A.Dr. of L.S: Honestus 3p. and end. Relative to the resignation of Mr. Pitt.
  - Letter to David Hall, March 13, 20, 1762; 7" x 8 3/4"; Strahan, William, 1715-1785
    London, A.L.S. 3p. and add. Refers to his letter to the editor of the London Chronicle, signed "Honestus," Oct.19, 1761. Mentions Dr. Franklin Business. Mentions W. Franklin. FILM54-61 FRAME69
  - Letter to David Hall, April 6, 1762; 7" x 8 3/4"; Strahan, William, 1715-1785
    London, A.L.S. 2p. and add. Introduces John Menzies. Adds a short note to Mrs. Hall.
  - Letter to David Hall, June 12, 1762; 8" x 12"; Strahan, William, 1715-1785
    London, A.L.S. 1p. and add. Is at Dr. Franklin's English politics. FILM54-61 FRAME 70
  - Letter to Davie [Hall], Aug. 10, 1762; 7 1/4" x 8 3/4"; Strahan, William, 1715-1785
    London, A.L.S. 4p. Praise of Dr. Franklin who carries this letter. Business. FILM54-61 FRAME 71
  - Letter to Davie [Hall], Oct. 20, 1762; 7 1/4" x 8 3/4"; Strahan, William, 1715-1785
    London, A.L.S. 2p. and end. Dr. Franklin; William Franklin's appointment as governor of New Jersey. Business. Mentions Mrs. Franklin. FILM54-61 FRAME 72
  - Letter to David Hall, Nov. 1, 1762; 7 1/4" x 8 3/4"; Strahan, William, 1715-1785
    London, A.L.S. 1p. and add. Inquires about Dr. Franklin; Sends letter by Gov. Franklin. Politics. FILM54-61 FRAME 73
  - Letter to Davie [Hall], May 10, 1763; 7 1/2" x 10"; Strahan, William, 1715-1785
    London, A.L.S. 3p. and end. Mentions Benjamin and William Franklin English politics. Business. FILM54-61 FRAME 74
  - Letter to David Hall, June 29, 1763; 7 1/4" x 8 3/4"; Strahan, William, 1715-1785
    London, A.L.S. 3p. and add. Compliments to Dr. Franklin and the governor. Business. Mentions W. Franklin and the Library company. FILM54-61 FRAME 75
  - Letter to David Hall, July 12, 1763; 7 1/2" x 10"; Strahan, William, 1715-1785
    London, A.L.S. 1p. and add. "Copy." Business. Politics.
  - Letter to David Hall, July 16, 1763; 7 1/4" x 8 3/4"; Strahan, William, 1715-1785
    London, A.L.S. 1p. and add. Mentions Dr. Franklin. Business. FILM54-61 FRAME76
  - Letter to David Hall, Aug. 12, 1763; 7" x 12"; Strahan, William, 1715-1785
    London, A.L.S. 1p. and add. "Copy." Politics. Business.
  - Letter to David Hall, Aug. 23, 1763; 7 1/4" x 8 3/4"; Strahan, William, 1715-1785
    London, A.L.S. 1p. and add. "All my politics are in the inclosed letter to Dr. Franklin..." Business. FILM54-61 FRAME 77
  - Letter to William Strahan, Aug. 24, 1763; Hall, David, 1714-1772
    Philadelphia, L. 1p. Business.
  - Letter to Davie [Hall], March 23, 1764; 7 1/4" x 9"; Strahan, William, 1715-1785
    London, A.L.S. 6p. and end. Mentions Dr. Franklin. Politics. Business. Mentions Wilkes, William and Mrs. Franklin. FILM54-61 FRAME 78
  - Letter to David Hall, June 4, 1764; 7 1/4" x 9"; Strahan, William, 1715-1785
    London, A.L.S. 3p. and add. ---- copy of letter on same sheet with letter from Strahan to Hall, June 30, 1764. L. 2p. 7 3/4" x 12 1/2" FILM54-61 FRAME 79
  - Letter to David Hall, June 30, 1764; 7 3/4" x 12 1/2"; Strahan, William, 1715-1785
    London, A.L.S. 1p. and add. ---- Copy of same letter. L.S. 2p. and add. 7 1/4" x 12" FILM54-61 FRAME80
  - Letter to Davie [Hall], Sept. 19, 1764; 7-1/4x9; Strahan, William, 1715-1785
    London, A.L.S. 3p. Mentions Dr. Franklin. Business. Politics. FILM54-61 FRAME81
  - Letter to David Hall, Oct. 13, 1764; 7 1/4" x 9"; Strahan, William, 1715-1785
    London, A.L.S. 3p. and add. Mentions Benjamin and William Franklin. FILM54-61 FRAME 82. Business.
  - Letter to David Hall, Nov. 30, Dec. 6, 1764; Strahan, William, 1715-1785
    General note
    Loose correspondence
  - Letter to [David Hall], Dec. 14, 1765; 7 1/4" x 9"; Strahan, William, 1715-1785
    Postcript of A.L. 2p., end. Dr. Franklin "under deep concern for the present distracted state of America." Comments on Hall's discontinuance of his paper. Stamp act. FILM54-61 FRAME86
  - Letter to [David] Hall, Jan. 16, 1770; 7" x 9"; Strahan, Margaret Pen
    London, A.L.S. 3p. and add. Family news. Mentions Dr. Franklin. Regards to Mrs. Franklin. FILM54-61 FRAME88
  - Letter to David Hall, July 7, 1770; Strahan, William, 1715-1785
  - Letter to David Hall, Aug. 19, 24, 1770; Strahan, William, 1715-1785
  - Letter to Davie [Hall], Jan. 2, 1771; 7 1/4" x 9"; Strahan, William, 1715-1785
    London, A.L.S. 3p. and end. Business. Family. Politics. Mentions Gov. Franklin. FILM54-family FRAME 32
  - Letter to [David Hall], March 19, 1772; Strahan, William, 1715-1785
  - Letter to Davie [Hall], Aug. 31, 1772; 7 1/4" x 9"; Strahan, William, 1715-1785
    London, A.L.S. 2p. English politics. Mentions Dr. Franklin. FILM54-61 FRAME 87
  - Letter to William Hall, July 6, 1774; 7 1/4" x 9"; Strahan, William, 1715-1785
    London, A.L.S. 1p. and add. Business. Politics.
  - Letter to William Hall, Jan. 5, 1775; 7 1/4" x 8 3/4"; Strahan, William, 1715-1785
    London, A.L.S. 2p. and end. Has a seat in the House of Commons. Mentions Gov. Franklin. Business. FILM54-family FRAME33
  - Letter to William Hall, Feb. 6, 1775; Strahan, William, 1715-1785